sofitel.com 2009-05-07

# Sofitel: information relating to security and confidentiality

To earn your trust, we promise that, on Sofitel.com and on the Accorhotels websites, we will do everything we can to make the reservation process secure and to protect your personal information.

## Your personal information

### Collecting the information

You are asked to provide us with personal information in the following instances:

  * when you reserve a hotel room or an airline ticket
  * when you register on our site, subscribe to our site newsletter, or take part in a contest
  * when you take part in a survey or if you contact us with a question or a problem.

### Use of the information

Your personal information is used solely:

  * to complete and guarantee reservations you make on our site
  * to simplify browsing and making reservations on our sites (recognition) and to provide the best service possible
  * for our administrative management and internal marketing analysis
  * to inform you by e-mail, if you have so agreed when registering on our site, of our special offers and promotions, news about our site, and to reserve the special advantages you are entitled to.

Your personal information will, under no circumstances, be transmitted to a third party; it will remain exclusively reserved to internal use.

### Modification of information

In conformance with Article 34 of the law on "Informatique et Libertés" (Computer Technology and Freedom), you have the right to access, modify, rectify and delete data pertaining to you.

To exercise that right, please contact:

Direction Générale Internet Accor  
Immeuble Odyssey  
110 avenue de France  
75210 Paris Cedex 13  
France

For more information on this law, you may visit the CNIL website.

If you are already registered on our site, you can modify your personal data at any time by accessing your profile after entering your User ID.

### Protection of information

To know more about our security system, click here.

## Cookies

When you visit our websites, a persistent cookie (a small text file) is created and saved on your computer's hard drive. The cookie makes it possible to recognize you when you visit our site so that we can improve and personalize your online experience.

We also collect technical information on your computer each time you open a page during your visit to our sites. This information includes your IP (Internet Protocol) address, the operating system used, the type of browser, and a Web site address of reference, if need be. We collect this information to improve the quality of your visit to our site and do not sell or transfer this information to third parties.

We use a Web site analytics tool called Xiti which provides a set of data and tracks how visitors use our site. When you visit our site, we create cookies to record and receive non personally identifiable information concerning your searches on the site. The Xiti tool enables us to improve your online experience and make our site more user friendly. It is never used to collect personal information pertaining to you and is never compared with your user profile if you are registered on our site.

Most browsers automatically accept these cookies, but you can delete them or have them automatically refused. As each browser is different, you should refer to the ""Help"" section on your browser toolbar to find out how to set your preferences regarding cookies. However, you may not be able to use certain features on our site if you choose not to accept cookies.

## E-mails

If you sign up on our site to receive our newsletters, we send you information by e-mail that we think will be of interest to you. To better meet your needs, we monitor the number of clicks on the hyperlinks in the newsletters. The agent who manages our newsletter mailings is not allowed to use any personal information that may be collected.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletters, you can unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the link provided at the end of the newsletter.

If you are registered on our site, you can unsubscribe at any time by modifying your personal data after entering your User ID.

## Security

To guarantee your security and ensure greater confidentiality, our Web site uses SSL encryption software (126 bits). Your bank account details and any other information you input when filling in different forms are automatically encrypted and protected during transmission over the network.

SSL automatically encrypts the information you input before it is transmitted over the network. The information can only be decrypted by using a unique key once it has arrived on our server. Developed by Netscape, SSL is the most widely used and successful secure transaction system today.

In order to offer you the best tool possible, we will continue to monitor and analyze future security systems, which will be implemented as soon as they are developed.

To use this system, you simply need to verify that your browser is compatible (in general, version 3 and better). You do this by checking if you see one of these icons either at the lower left of your screen (for Netscape) or the lower right (for Microsoft Internet Explorer).
